Connecticut Women's Educational And Legal Fund Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund Records.
1972-1988
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund.
2 linear feet.
MSS19890070
The Connecticut Women's Educational and legal Fund (CWEALF), a non-profit public interest law firm, was founded in 1973. CWEALF helps women gain equality under the law. Its establishment resulted from sex discrimination in mortgage lending, when attorneys from the Status of Women Committee of the Connecticut Bar Association joined forces and worked for the passage of the Connecticut Equal Credit Act.
History
The Connecticut Women's Educational and Legal Fund (CWEALF), a non-profit public interest law firm, was founded in 1973. CWEALF helps women gain equality under the law. Its establishment resulted from sex discrimination in mortgage lending, when attorneys from the Status of Women Committee of the Connecticut Bar Association joined forces and worked for the passage of the Connecticut Equal Credit Act.
CWEALF focuses upon discrimination in such areas as education, employment, insurance, and health care. Other concerns include reproductive rights and lesbian and gay rights. The firms uses four different methods to achieve its goal of equal rights: speaking and training; education; counseling and referral services; and litigation.
Scope and Content
The collection contains records of speaking engagements, films, referral lists, and legal testimony; as well as committee reports, outreach efforts and curriculum. Also included are conference and workshop materials, lists of contacts, flyers, worksheets, publications, and Title XX data.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to alternative lifestyles, politics and publications. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Women—Legal status, laws, etc.—Connecticut.; Women—Connecticut—Economic conditions.; Sex discrimination in consumer credit—Law and legislation—Connecticut.; Credit—Law and legislation—Connecticut.; Sex discrimination in employment—Law and legislation—Connecticut.; Sex discrimination in education—Law and legislation—Connecticut.; Sex discrimination against women—Connecticut.; Women's health services—Connecticut.; Sex discrimination in insurance—Connecticut.; Public interest.; Practice of law—Connecticut.; Discrimination in mortgage loans—Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Administrative Records.
Occupations:
Public interest law firm.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives department (ow Archives & Special Collections) of the University Libraries in March 1989.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1972-1988
  - Administrative
    - Community agencies, 1981 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Created equal: requests for “Sex: Female” and Title IX Bulletin, 1978-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Divorce/Separation support groups, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Film listing, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Film loans, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Films: state resources, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Interns, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Legislation/Testimony, 1978-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Public speaking forms, 1982-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 9-11)
    - Workplace Hustle, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Affirmative Action
    - Education material, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Education
    - Connecticut Three Year State plan for the Administration of Vocational Education, 1986-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Curriculum, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Education Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Education Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Education program, 1973-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Education for employment, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Mini-course correspondence (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Mini-Course outline and curriculum guide, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Outreach education program, 1980-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Outreach Letters, 1980-1985 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Peer local replication study: preliminary data, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Sex equity in education, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Title IX Interagency Committee, 1972-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Lesbian and Gay Rights
    - AIDS information, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - Conference evaluations, 1986 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Conference materials, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - Conference money, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Presenters and keynote, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - Registration forms, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - Workshop materials, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - Hartford Women's Coalition for Municipal Elections
    - Candidate's responses, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - Pregnancy Rights Project
    - American College of Ob/Gyn: Dr. Richard Jones, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - Bureau of Maternal/Child Health: Dr. Stuart Wolff, Director, 1983-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - Clark Clinic: Ella-Lee Gadson, Director, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - Hartford Teenage Parents Program: Mary King, MSW, S. McNally, Director, 1984-1985 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - Hartford YWCA: Reisa Gold, Fitness Director, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - Hispanic Health Council: Ella Vega/Ruth Martinez, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - New Haven (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - Pregnancy flyer, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Pregnancy project, 1983-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - Pregnancy Discrimination Act worksheet, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - Pregnancy rights file: general, 1983-1984 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - Visiting Nurses Association: Mary Crose, Hispanic Unit, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - Young Parents Program, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - Publications and press releases
    - Articles, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - Brochures, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - Bulletins, 1977-1979 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - Bulletins, 1976, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 52-53)
    - Newsletters, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - Other paste-ups, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - Other public service announcements, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - Rape and law bulletin, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Sexual Harassment
    - Coalition against Sexual Harassment, 1981-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - Conference with OCR, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Event in New Haven, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - Hartford, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - Hartford Training, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Mid-Fairfield, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - Sexual Harassment project, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - Sexual harassment in our schools, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - Title XX, 1978-1979 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - Waterbury Program, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
  - Special Events
    - Birthday in the park, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - CML breakfast, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - “Hartford Seven” film, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
  - Special Events
    - Outlaw fund-raiser, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - Pay Equity conference, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - Second annual “Friends of WIN” dinner, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 73)